你好，你们这些漂亮的人都知道在上一段视频中你们了解到了INTOX手册的结构
Hello you beautiful people know in the last video you learned about the structure of the intox manual
你也看到了它被分成八个部分的方式。
and you saw the way that it was broken up into eight sections.
这8秒中的每一秒都涉及Linux体验的不同部分。
And those eight seconds each deal with a different part of the Linux experience.
现在我们将把上一段视频中的理论付诸实践。
Now we're going to take that theory from the last video and we're going to turn it into practice.
在这段视频中。
In this video.
因此，在此视频中，您可以了解如何搜索时间、发现新命令以及如何访问
So in this video you can learn how to search the minute and discover new commands and how to access
这些命令的手册页。
the manual pages for those commands.
你还将学习如何阅读它们，这样你就可以走出去独立学习
And you're also going to learn how to read them so that you can go out there and independently learn
如何使用新东西。
how to use new stuff.
因此，在本视频结束时，您将可以独立搜索新命令并了解
So by the end of this video you'll have the independence to search for new commands and learn about
他们是如何工作的。
how they work.
这将使你处于主导地位，因为它使你有可能获得更多
And this is going to put you in the driver's seat because it makes it possible for you to gain more
控制您的Linux系统，因为您可以开始独立学习一切是如何工作的
control of your Linux system because you can start learning independently about how everything works
而不是等待您随机遇到学习新命令的随机机会。
rather than waiting for a random chances that you randomly bump into learning new commands.
您可以在学习和开发Linux操作时发挥更积极的作用
You can take a lot more of an active role in your learning and your development of the Linux operating
系统。
system.
所以，让我们继续直截了当地谈吧。
So let's go ahead and get right into it.
好的，既然你知道手册被分成了八个部分，你怎么知道是哪个部分呢？
OK so now that you know that the manual is broken up into eight sections How would you know what section
去找你要找的东西。
to look in to find what you're looking for.
好的，假设您想要查找有关首先搜索手册的哪个命令的信息
Well let's say that you wanted to look up information about the which command first to search the manual
您必须使用man命令，即man命令是单词Manual的缩写。
you would have to use the man command that a man command is short for the word manual.
基本上，它是处理与手册有关的所有事情的命令。
And it's the command that deals with everything to do with the manual basically.
这就是它们实际上被称为手册页的原因，因为它是man命令查看
And this is why they're actually called man pages because it's the man command that looks through the
手册。
manual.
好的。
OK.
这就是命令名。
Now that's the command name.
所以我们对此很在行。
So we're good at that.
现在，如果有必要，我们需要给它任何选择。
Now we need to give it any options if necessary.
Mark，您要使用k选项，这是与搜索有关的选项。
Mark are you going to use the k option which is what deals with searching.
好的，我们现在有一些未命名的选项。
OK so we've got some unnamed options now.
它需要一个输入，我们要给出的输入是搜索词。
It needs an input and the input that we're going to give is the search term.
所以我们输入哪一个。
So we type which.
好的。
OK.
所以我们有一个命令名，我们有我们的选项，我们有我们的输入，相同的通用结构
So we got a command name we've got our options we've got our inputs the same general structure that
我之前是在设置，但现在我们实际上是在用那个人来搜索手册
I was setting up before but now what we're doing actually is using the man come on to search the manual
对于这个搜索词，这里的搜索词称为Which。
for this search term the search term here called which.
会通读手册，找出任何可能与搜索相关的信息
Is going to look all the way through the manual and find anything that might be relevant to that search
时间到了。
time.
它就像你自己的迷你手册搜索引擎。
It's like your own mini search engine for your manual.
因此，如果表示，我们在这里得到了相当多的输出行。
So if Representer we get quite a few lines of output here.
好的。
OK.
让我们来看看左边的是什么。
So let's let's have a look at what this is on the left here.
您将获得某些手册页的名称。
You're going to get the names of certain manual pages.
好的。
OK.
其中的每一个都是适用于该搜索词的手册页。
Every single one of these is a manual page that is appropriate to this search term.
好的。
OK.
在右边，您可以看到有关实际页面的概要，这样您就可以选择哪个页面可能是
And on the right you get a bit of a synopsis about the actual page so you can pick which one might be
非常合适。
most appropriate.
好的。
OK.
另一件事在这里的括号里，你可以得到手册的章节编号，那一页
And the other thing is in the parentheses here you get the section number of the manual that that page
是很流行的。
is in.
例如，手册页上的这个命令在手册的第一部分，这意味着它是一个
So for example this command at manual page is in the first section of the manual which means it's a
用户命令，而此命令位于手册的第8部分，这意味着它是一个更多的系统
user command whereas this one is in the 8th section of the manual which means that it is a more system
行政管理之类的事情。
administrative kind of thing.
这在第5节中介绍了文件文件配置，说明了文件的结构
And this one is in Section 5 which is going to be a file file configuration how the files are structured
这些内容是关于文件如何组织的信息，以便我们可以一目了然地看到
and things are that information about how files are structured so that we can actually see at a glance
不管它是否真的适合我们的需要。
whether it actually suits our needs or not.
如果我们决定要进一步观察，这个看起来就是我们要找的
And if we decide that we want to take a further look it seems like this one is exactly what we're looking
转到“使用命令”部分，它是一个定位命令的命令。
forward to the use a command section and it's a command that locates a command.
实际上，我们可以通过再次使用地图来更深入地了解这一点。
We can actually take a deeper look at that by using the map again.
然后是区号。
Then the section number.
因此，节号是1，然后我们键入搜索词。
So the section number is 1 and then we type the search term.
左边的页面名称是什么。
And so the page name which is on the left there which is which.
好的，如果我按回车键。
OK and if I press enter.
我们已经打开了Which命令的手册页。
We've opened up the manual page for the which command.
它只是很小，一旦我们打开它，关闭它并返回，我们只需按Q键
It's only very small and once we've opened that to close it and get back out we just press the q key
或者按字母Q，我就会回到我的命令行上。
on the on the keyboards or press the letter Q And I'm back on my command line.
例如，我们可以在这里打开这一小部分，这是灵魂的事情，通过做人类6号，因为它是
So for example we could open up this small section here this soul thing by doing MAN 6 because it's
第6节盐，我按Enter，它会打开盐手册页面，您可以在
Section 6 salt and I press enter and it opens up that that manual page for salt which you can see at
上面就在那里。
the top right there.
好的。
OK.
现在，由于手册的第一部分使用非常频繁，您通常不必键入数字
Now because the first section of the manual is used so often you don't usually have to type the number
即便如此，我也可以直接输入单词man，而不是输入man 1，这是一个不错的Shoko。
one even so instead of typing Man 1 which is a nice Shoko I can just type the word man.
你会打字吗伙计。
Can you type man.
它将打开同一页相同的手册页，您可以看到它确实在第节中
Which which will open up the same page the same manual page and you can see that it is indeed in Section
1.
好的，这是一条捷径，如果你看到第一节中有东西的话。
OK so that's a shortcut if you see that something is in Section 1.
您不需要说出您只需输入页面的实际名称即可。
You don't need to talk the one you just type the actual name of the page.
因此，就像一个页面一样，我们的LCF是正确的。
So like a page we've got LCF right.
LCF位于第1节man LCF中，我们可以看到，在第1节的LCF手册页中，我们都知道这意味着
LCF is in section 1 man LCF and we see that we all know in the LCF man page in section 1 which means
这是一个用户命令。
that it's a user command.
好的。
OK.
这就是你打开手册页的方式。
So that's how you would open up a manual page.
接下来，我们来看看你们会怎么读这篇文章。
And up next now we're going to take a look at how you would actually read it.
好的。
OK.
因此，我们来看一下Which命令的手册页。
So let's take a look at the man page for the which command.
所以我要和你谈谈男人。
So I'm going to talk man.
然后是哪个。
And then which.
因为这实际上是我最近用过的一个命令，所以我可以只按箭头
And because it's actually a command that I've used very recently I could have just pressed the arrow
按几次键，我就会返回相同的结果。
key a couple of times and I get back to the same result.
好的。
OK.
所以我按了man，然后再按Enter，我们就打开了手册页面。
So I press man which press enter and we've opened up the manual page.
现在我们可以看到，这个手册页面实际上被分成了顶部的以下几个部分
Now we can see that this manual page is actually broken up into the following sections of the top we've
有了名字，我们就有了一个概要，然后我们就有了一个描述，我们可以选择。
got name then we've got a synopsis then we've got a description that we've got options.
那我们就有出口状态了。
Then we've got exit status.
好的，现在手册页的章节可能包含所有示例。
OK now the sections a man page may include all examples.
另请参阅环境一节关于博格斯的事情关于办公室的事情关于报告的事情
See also section an environment section things about Bogues things about office things about reporting
BUGS历史命令版权的东西。
bugs history of the command copyright things.
诸如此类的东西。
Stuff like that.
好的，但这就是我们在这个特定的手册页面中看到的内容，因为它们的结构并不总是一样的
OK but this is what we get in this specific manual page because they're not always structured the same
但是他们通常遵循这种结构。
way but they usually follow this kind of structure.
好的。
OK.
现在，在Name部分中，我们可以看到我们正在处理Which命令，并且我们可以看到一些关于
Now in the name section we see that we are dealing with the which command and we see a little bit about
它的作用，这实际上是我们一开始搜索手册时出现的。
what it does and this is actually what came up when we searched the manual in the first place.
好的，这就是出现的情况。
OK this is exactly what came up.
我们看到了名字，然后在右手边有一小段信息。
We saw the name and then this little piece of information on the right hand side.
好的。
OK.
现在，在描述部分中，这是您真正了解常见功能的地方
Now in the description section this is where you this is where you really see what the common does in
每个重要部分的描述部分，它为您提供了更深入的描述
the description sections of every important section and it gives you a much more in-depth description
指挥官到底在做什么。
of what the commander actually does.
对于任何命令，这可能是手册页中最有用的部分之一。
This is likely going to be one of the most useful parts of the man page for any command.
因为它将试图用通俗易懂的英语来解释指挥官们。
And as it will try to explain what the commanders in plain English.
好的，您已经在那里得到了哪个命令的描述，在这里您已经在概要部分中得到了这些
OK so you've got the which command description there and here you've got these in the synopsis section
我们可以看到如何实际使用该命令的布局。
we can see a layout of how to actually use the command.
所以，当我告诉您每个命令的结构都不同时，您需要阅读
So German when I was telling you the each command is structured differently and you need to read the
手册页，了解如何使用命令。
manual pages to see how to use a command.
这是手册页的一部分，它将告诉您如何使用该命令。
Well this is the section of the manual page that will tell you how to use the command.
提纲部分。
The synopsis section.
因此，对于哪种类型，我们可以看到第一种类型，哪种类型可以。
So for the which come on we can see the first type which OK.
命令名称，然后我们在一些方括号中看到A选项，该选项将立即进入
The command name and then we see the A option in some square brackets which will come into in a minute
然后是某种文件名。
and then some kind of file name.
然后是三个点，尽管后来也被称为省略号。
And then three dots although also known as an ellipsis afterwards.
所以让我来解释一下这东西是什么意思。
So let me explain what this stuff means.
好的，首先我们输入他们只需输入的内容，然后我们有一个选项，这是可选的。
OK so first we enter the which come they will just type which then we have the option which is optional.
现在我们知道它是可选的，因为它在手册页的方括号内。
Now we know it's optional because it's inside the square brackets in a man page.
如果有东西在方括号里，那就意味着它是可选的。
If something is inside square brackets that means it's optional.
好的，您不必输入，但是可以输入。
OK you don't have to enter it but you can.
好的。
OK.
接下来，一旦我们输入了我们的可选选项。
Now next after that once we've entered our optional option we.
接下来，您必须输入您实际要查找的命令的名称。
Next you have to enter the name of a command that you're actually looking for.
现在你可以看到了，所以你在寻找的时候输入一个名字，例如，它可能是衰变，然后是回声。
Now you can see so you enter a name when you looking for example which may be decay and then echo.
好的。
OK.
那会告诉你ECHO命令在哪里。
That would show you where the echo command was.
但是你也可以看到这个省略号，哦，这三个点，这三个点意味着你可以输入更多
But you also see this ellipsis Oh these three dots that these three dots mean that you can enter more
而不是一个文件名。
than one file name.
因此，换句话说，该命令可以接受多个输入。
So in other words the command can take more than one input.
现在事情开始变得有条不紊了。
Things are starting to fall into place now.
好的，那么您如何知道该命令接受多少输入呢？您将查看您查看的手册页吗
Right so how do you know how many inputs the command takes will you look at the man page you look at
大纲，它会告诉你需要多少输入。
the synopsis and it will tell you how many inputs it takes.
好的。
OK.
现在只是为了证明这一点。
Now just to prove it.
好的。
OK.
只要证明这一点就行了。
Just prove this.
我们要把我们在这里学到的东西。
We're going to take what we've learned here.
我们将会应用它。
And we're going to apply it.
好的，我现在要回去通过按住Ctrl来清除屏幕显示，我们将
OK so I'm going to go back and clear the screen presence by holding control in now and we're going to
请看，我们将尝试并使用该命令来同时查找DATA命令和命令。
see we're going to try and use the command to find the data command and the command at the same time.
好的。
OK.
所以我们使用了Which命令。
So we've used the which command.
我们没有给它这个选项，但我们也没有必要，因为这只是一个可选的选项，因为我们
We didn't give it the option but we didn't have to because it's just option just optional because we
因为它在方括号里，我们给它起了一个很远的名字，然后我说如果我们
because it was in the square brackets and we've given it a one far name and then another I say if we
按Enter键，我们看到有两个输出，然后找到了date命令的位置
press enter that we see that we get two outputs and then it's found the locations of the date command
然后是计数命令。
and then the count command.
我们不需要运行该命令两次，因为如果我们查看手册页，它会告诉我们实际上可以
We didn't need to run the command twice because if we look at the man page it tells us we can actually
为其指定多个文件名。
give it more than one file name.
好的。
OK.
所以这真的很有用，也许不是我们不知道必须要做的事情。
So that's really really useful and maybe not maybe something we wouldn't have known had to do.
我们还没有看手册页。
We had not looked at the man page.
就像我说的，主页方括号里的东西会重新打开。
And as I said the things inside square brackets in the main page will be opened up again.
方括号内的东西是可选的。
Things inside the square brackets are optional.
这类东西你不一定要，但你可以拥有，如果你想知道它有什么用
This kind of stuff you don't have to have but you can have and if you want to know what it does you
只需转到选项部分即可。
just go to the Options section.
因此，如果我放入选项，它将打印每个参数的所有匹配路径名，因此所有匹配
So if I put in the option it says it'll print all the matching pathnames of each argument so all matching
路径名so是所有人的缩写。
pathnames so is short for all.
所以我能做的就是打字，我能做的就是打字。
So what I could do is I could type which I could do.
日期和日期是什么，但我会打破折号。
Which date and cow but I could type dash.
看看这会不会有什么不同。
And see if that does any difference.
实际上，这并没有什么不同。
It actually and it doesn't make any difference.
但它将向我们展示所有不同的所有不同的结果。
But it will show us all of the different all of the different results.
所以你可能知道，当我告诉你关于搜索的时候，在路径上搜索，也许这会让我们
So maybe you know when I told you about searching searching on the path maybe this will allow us to
如果文件夹的名称与之前相同，请查看路径中后面的文件夹
look in folders that were later on in the path if they had the same name as where they were earlier
在……上面。
on.
好的。
OK.
所以我们走吧。
So there we go.
现在手册页上还有其他的符号，比如尖括号。
Now there's other the symbols in the manual pages such as angle brackets.
所以这类事情。
So these kind of things.
正确的。
Right.
所以如果你在手册页里面有东西的话。
So if you have something inside here inside the manual page.
所以如果我们有这样的东西，然后是这样的，然后你有一些在尖括号里的东西。
So if we have like which And then it was like this and then you had something ok inside angle brackets.
尖括号内的任何内容都是必填项。
Anything inside the angle brackets is mandatory.
这意味着你必须拥有它。
That means you have to have it.
好的。
OK.
所以，如果你在尖括号里看到什么东西，那就意味着你必须拥有它，你不能错过它，请访问
So if you see something inside angle brackets that means you have to have it and you can't miss it at
好的。
all right.
所以请记住这一点。
So just bear that in mind.
还有烟斗角色。
There's also the pipe character.
所以如果我在这里有一个选项，比如说你有f选项。
So if I have an option here and it was something like say you had the f option.
好的。
OK.
因为在两个选项之间有一个竖线字符。
Because there's a pipe character between the two options.
这意味着好的，你必须选择一个或另一个。
That means OK you have to pick one or the other.
好的，管子指的是一个或另一个。
OK so the pipe means one or the other.
你不能两者兼得。
You cannot have both.
所以我不能打字我不能打字哪个是死亡日期。
So I couldn't type I couldn't type which which Dasch a death date.
好的，我必须输入哪个破折号A或哪个破折号f不能同时拥有。
OK I would have to type which dash A or which dash f couldn't have both.
如果你看到里面有东西就会这样。
That's what happens if you see something inside.
内角括号。
Inside angle brackets.
好的，再来一次，我再想一想。
OK some second time I think again.
所以角括号之间有一根管子。
So the angle brackets with a pipe in between them.
好的，那么到目前为止，贝杜因。
OK so what Beduin so far.
好的。
OK.
这可能是你大多数时候都会想到的。
It's probably what you'll come up with most of the time.
所以这些都是你会看到的不同的东西。
So these are all the different things that you'll see.
你会知道名字的。
You'll have the name.
你有一些选择。
You have some options.
它会告诉您哪些是可选的，哪些是您需要的，哪些是不能组合的
It will tell you which ones are optional and which ones you need and which ones cannot be combined with
其他。
others.
您将看到方括号内可能是咒语的东西，后面可能是带圆点的任何东西
You will see things that may be a mantra inside square brackets and anything with a dot dot dot after
这意味着你可以拥有不止一件东西。
it means you can have more than one thing.
所以，如果它是这样的可悲，它是一个文件名，然后点，这意味着你可以有更多
So if it's sad like this it was a file name was in it and then dot dot dot that means you can have more
当您使用此命令时，请使用一个以上的文件名。
than one file name when you use this command.
现在我实际上要在度假胜地的资源部分为这堂课设置一个PTF，它列出了
Now I'm actually going to put a PTF in the resort in the resource section for this lecture that lists
不同符号的含义。
what the different symbols mean.
因此，如果您需要快速刷新，您可以使用它，但这几乎就是您需要记住的全部内容。
So you can use it if you ever need a quick refresher but it's pretty much all you need to remember.
好的。
OK.
只有方括号中的任何内容都是可选的。
Just the anything in square brackets is optional.
在它之间有一根管子，你只能有一根或另一根，任何东西都可以，任何角度的东西都可以成正方形。
And with a pipe in between it you can only have one or the other anything and square anything in angle
方括号是必填项。
brackets is mandatory.
我认为有了圆点之后，你可以多次使用，因为你需要做的几乎就是
And I think with dot dot dot after it you can use more than once because pretty much all you need to
我知道。
know.
如果您想知道如何查找不同选项的作用，请向下滚动到选项部分
And if you want to know how to look up what different options do to scroll down to the Options section
在主页中，它将确切地告诉您如何使用它们。
in the main page and it'll tell you exactly how to use them all.
好的。
OK.
太棒了，我们在这段视频中谈到了很多东西，你应该开始感受到更多
Awesome So we've covered a whole lot of stuff in this video and you should start feeling a lot more
轻松使用本视频中已有的命令行。
comfortable using the command line already in this video.
所以必须使用带有k选项的man命令搜索手册，然后您就可以给出它了
So have to search the manual using the man command with the k option and after that you can give it
任何你想要的搜索词。
any search term that you want.
该命令将在手册中搜索该搜索词，并为您提供结果列表以及
And the command will search the manual for that search term and give you a list of results as well as
这些结果是什么，以及它们在手册页面的哪个部分。
what those results are and where section of the manual page they're in.
因此，我必须访问这些特定的手册页，以及如何阅读它们以了解特定的命令结构。
So I had to access those specific manual pages and also how to read them for specific command structure.
因此，我们看到了Tota如何使用其手册页实际使用Which命令。
So we saw how Tota actually use the which command using its manual page.
我们看到手册页上可能会出现不同的符号来告诉您如何使用它。
And we saw the different symbols that might come up in the manual page to tell you how to use it.
但我在参考资料部分附上了这段视频的小抄，我强烈建议您
But I've attached cheat sheet in the resources section for this video that I massively encourage you
使用并保存在手边，因为它将为您解释每个不同的符号
to use and keep on hand because it's going to give you an explanation of each of the different symbols
它可能会显示在手册页上，这样您就可以将其放在手边。
that might show up in a manual page so that you can keep that to hand.
你知道，要确保你没有忘记任何东西。
And you know make sure that you don't forget anything.
而是为了确保你不会忘记任何东西。
But to ensure that you don't forget anything.
接下来我们要进行一些练习，我们要做的是我们一起去，我们
Up next we're going to have some practice what we're going to do is we're going to go together and we're
接下来，我们将搜索一个新的命令，我们将阅读它是如何工作的。
going to look at we're going to search for a new command and we're going to read about how it works.
我们可以查看它的手册页面，我们将学习并实际应用它并展示
We can look at it's manual page and we're going to take that learning and actually apply it and show
您将如何使用您以前从未见过的手册页，并学习如何使用它。
you how how you would take a man page that you've never seen before and learn how to use it.
因此，我们将应用我们在这节课中学到的关于阅读手册页面的知识，并应用
So we're going to be applying what we've learned in this lecture about reading manual pages and apply
把它转移到一个全新的指挥部，然后一起通过。
it to a completely new command and go through it together.
在那之后，你肯定会觉得，嘿，任何命令或我来过的任何手册页面
And after that you should definitely feel as though hey any command or any manual page that I've come
我会知道怎么读，知道怎么用，这会大大增强你的信心
up against I'll know how to read and know how to use which is going to give you a massive boost of confidence
并且极大地增强了您的独立性，让您可以探索和了解更多关于Linux操作系统的知识。
and a massive boost of independence for you to explore and learn more about the Linux operating system.
那么，让我们继续跳到下一个视频，来一些超级酷炫的练习。
So let's go ahead and jump into the next video and get some super super cool practice.